In the not so distant future,
when the corporate networks
fill the earth with electronic
and optical communication lines
but society has not yet been
too computerized
to erase nations and races...
All patrolling air units,
a 208 is in progress
in the c-13 district of Newport city.
Air space over this area
will be closed. Repeat.
All patrolling air units,
a 208 is in progress
in the c-13 district of Newport city.
Air space over this area
will be closed.
There's no need for concern.
Our country is quite capable
of covering its tracks.
That's why you need me, right?
Depends on how you look at it.
At any rate, any program has its bugs,
and I would think that a man
of your capability could cure our problem.
You don't understand.
We aren't even sure that project 2501
really is a bug.
Originally, the purpose of this project...
Major kusanagi, section 6
is in position and ready to move in.
- Major, are you there?
- Yeah, I heard you.
I'm surprised you can hear anything.
What's with all the noise
in your brain today?
Must be a loose wire.
Don't you think
there's gonna be trouble later
if section 9 interferes with section 67
if section 6 manages to catch the bastard,
then all they can really do about it
is deport him.
Don't forget, we're section 9.
We'll clean it up.
We're the ones who get our hands dirty.
It's time now.
Let's move to the rendezvous point.
- What? The police here?
- Huh?
Stop it! Who told you to fire?
Put your guns down now!
Freezel
get your hands up!
I'm entitled to diplomatic immunity.
I want to talk to the person
in charge here.
Taking classified programmers
out of the country
compromises national security.
We can also have you brought up
on kidnapping charges.
You have no choice. Let him go.
Not possible.
Mr. daita wants political asylum from us
and we have his signed affidavit.
- What?
- I don't have to explain.
My country has the right, in accordance
with international law,
to offer anyone protection
and safe passage.
The affidavit is at the embassy.
I'll send you a copy in a couple of days.
Daita, you'll be killed if you return.
I'm warning you to watch your comments.
Our country is a peace-loving democracy.
Of course it is!
On!
The window. Shoot!
Fh?
I don't believe it.
Therm-optic camouflage.
Aramaki!
This is quite a surprise.
So what business
brings the chief of section 9
to the ministry of foreign affairs?
I need to ask you
about the secret talk
scheduled with the gavel Republic
tomorrow.
Procedure, of course.
Well, the regime that took over gavel
after the revolution
demands financial aid,
supposedly for redevelopment.
They boast democracy,
but they're no better than the last lot.
Now they feel entitled to funds
because of our past exploitation.
- No gratitude.
- What's the ministry going to do?
Well, there's a problem.
The leader of the former junta
that controlled their country
is here seeking political asylum.
You mean colonel malles, correct?
Yes, and that means we either
deny gavel the funds
and treat malles as a political refugee,
or help them and kick him out.
Personally, I'm inclined to deport him,
forcibly, if necessary,
but I'd have to come up with a politically
acceptable reason for it.
By the way, I want to thank you
for your help
with that other political asylum
situation.
Nakamura from section 6
wasn't so grateful.
But you realize that we in the diplomat
business must avoid messy situations.
Access.
We've lost response.
What's happened to the eeg output?
It's normal. I'll switch to simex mode.
In case you haven't been briefed,
this is the minister's interpreter.
Twenty-three minutes ago, her brain
was hacked into through a data line.
Foreign intelligence warned us
about this.
A hacker called the puppet master
has begun to infiltrate terminals
throughout our network.
We believe it's extremely likely
he'll target the secret talks that are
scheduled with the Republic of gavel.
As a precaution, we've put everyone
attending the talks under surveillance.
It's my suspicion that once he hacked
into her ghost,
he'd use her to assassinate
the key delegates.
So how much time do we have
before this hacker breaks through
her barrier program and reaches her ghost?
Roughly two hours.
He's using an old-fashioned has virus.
After that, we'll have
to break the connection
to avoid any danger to the system.
Batou and ishikawa are tracking the signal
source from their car. Contact them.
You know, I don't know what's going on.
Mind filling me in, major?
Are we talking about the puppet master,
the infamous mystery hacker?
Well, we don't know a lot either.
No clue about sex, age or background.
We think that he or she is American.
And it's the first time he's known
to show up here.
All we know for certain is, this person
is on the international most wanted list
for crimes including stock manipulation,
illegal information gathering,
political engineering,
several acts of terrorism.
So why the nickname?
The nickname "puppet master"
comes from the ghost hacking.
Well, if he's so skilled, how come
he's using an outdated ha3 virus?
Think about it a minute.
You have to figure he's either covering
his tracks or decoying us.
Even though a more current technique
would be harder to trace,
it might also arise suspicion about
colonel malles' role in this affair.
Are you saying that's the reason
he's using an old method,
just that no one would suspect malles?
Or maybe this is all an elaborate ruse
to make us think in that direction.
There's always a chance malles
is a pawn in this setup.
Now you're stretching it.
It's not like you have any hard evidence.
No, no evidence.
Just a whisper. I hear it in my ghost.
Which reminds me,
are you still using that revolver?
You should stop worrying about the
automatics jamming up.
I like my matever.
Well, effective stopping power is more
important than your preference in guns.
Since it's my ass on the line out there,
use the zasteber.
Yes, major.
There's something I've wanted to ask
ever since I started.
Why did you transfer a guy like me
from the police force?
- Because we need a guy like you.
- Huh?
Number one, you're an honest cop.
Number two, you've never
stepped out of line,
and three, you're a family man.
And except for the slight brain
augmentation,
your body is almost completely human.
If we all reacted the same way,
we'd be predictable,
and there's always more than one way
to view a situation.
What's true for the group is also true
for the individual.
It's simple... overspecialize
and you breed in weakness.
It's slow death.
- Dammit! Come on!
- I'll be right there!
Oh, for Christ's sake!
We're already 40 seconds late.
- Will you hurry it up?
- Hang on, I'm almost done.
It's gonna be one of those days.
Hey, sorry, pal.
My last partner got busted
working as an illegal alien.
Couldn't speak english
but he was a lot better than you are.
So what are you trying to find out so bad
you gotta ghost-hack
into your wife's mind for, huh?
My wife never has any time.
Now, all of a sudden she wants a divorce.
And to make matters worse,
my daughter, my only kid,
got it in her head that I'm the one
cheating on her mom.
What I don't get is, how did you get
your hands on a barrier breaker?
From this really nice fella.
I was in a bar and he overheard
my sob story.
I mentioned that my wife's lawyer stopped
me from seeing her and my daughter.
He must've felt sorry,
because he showed me how to hack in
from different places along the route.
It's hard to trace.
Asshole! You think you own the damn road?
It looks like we're not the only ones
who're in a hurry around here.
Nothing. Shit.
What's the point in us breaking our butts?
Every time we get to the source,
they're already long gone.
- We're just wasting our time.
- Don't quit yet.
Kusanagi and togusa are heading
fo the next area
the hacker's expected to access from.
Stay alert.
- What are we looking for, chief?
- Anything!
Like I said, a waste of time.
Dammit all to hell!
Oh, shit! I missed him!
Hey, pop, did you see anyone
using the phone over here?
- S07? Who wants to know?
- Just answer me!
Did you see someone or not?
Yeah. I saw the trash man making a call,
so I thought I had enough time
to bring my garbage down.
Hey! Can't you take this for me?
A trash truck? Clever.
It changes location every seven minutes.
Hq, patch me target info from the district
controlling that truck.
Eight refuse collection vehicles
are on duty in the surveillance area.
The target is number 58, a type c vehicle.
Give me the wheel.
Ishikawa, go check out
the trash collectors' homes.
Batou, cut the truck off
at its next stopping point.
It's possible they've come into contact
with someone.
Follow them, but take no action. Got it?
We've got the data
on the refuse collection points.
All points correspond to those locations
where we've traced back the calls.
The target has now stopped
at the next point.
Ha-3 access confirmed.
Hey! How about if I pick up
the trash on the second half of our round
and you make the calls?
Well?
Ain't no way I'm gonna be
your partner in crime.
It's your wife, you handle her.
Tell me, have you got
any children of your own?
You must be kidding.
Then I guess you can't understand how
a father would feel about his little girl.
She's my beautiful, precious angel.
- See?
- Get away!
I'm not interested in crap like that.
Yeah, vehicle 58.
Yeah, what can I... what's that?
What do the cops wanna know
our rounds for?
How would I know? Why're you asking me?
Oh, my god, they found out!
That guy who helped me, I gotta warn him!
Listen, we're gonna have
to pass up the next pickup.
What?
Target has deviated from route,
and is heading to its next designated
point at increased speed.
It wasn't me. There's no way
I could've been spotted.
They probably traced me
when I accessed
the sanitation department network.
Next time, use the back door.
Forget that now.
Just arrest them.
- You can drive now.
- Huh?
Hey, they know!
Christ! What the hell's he using?
That Van was armored!
Watch it! He's got high-velocity bullets.
Your car door won't stop them.
Hv ammo in a submachine pistol?
He's insane!
This guy is even wearing
some kind of therm-optics.
Keep on his tall.
I'll come around from the top.
Togusa, if you're still alive, get off
your ass and arrest those garbagemen.
Affirmative.
Yes, siree. The excitement
never stops.
It's the freshest in the city
at the lowest cost.
It's a bargain at twice the price.
Hey!
Police! Everybody get down!
Shit!
Get out of the fucking way!
I ook out!
- Aw! Out of ammo?
- Huh?
Got 'im, huh?
Well, the breech and the barrel are really
screwed up.
That's what happens when you use hv
bullets in one of these things. Oh, yeah.
It's no use arresting me!
I'm not talking to any goddamn cops!
Talk?
And just what are you gonna talk about?
You don't even know your own name,
you stupid dickhead!
Huh?
Can you remember your mother's name, or
what she looks like?
Or how about where you were born?
Don't you have any happy
childhood memories?
Do you even know who you are?
Ghost-hacked humans are so pathetic,
it's a shame.
And this poor bastard's been hacked
pretty badly.
We'll enter after the passengers
have gone into the building.
Squad b comes in from the rear,
and the rest of you go through the front.
Saito, have some of your men unplug
all cars parked in front of the house.
Begin recording.
Chief, a message for you
from headquarters.
Batou here. We've ID'd the man
the major caught.
- So who is he?
- He claims to be tsuan gen fang, age 28.
He's had prior convictions
of violating immigration law,
and illegal possession of firearms.
A member of a militant immigrant
organization.
About a week ago,
the military attache of the Republic
of gavel embassy commissioned him.
They made their choice
based on his criminal record
fo make an assault
on the upcoming secret meeting.
They were going to pay him $100,000.
Just another fantasy.
- And in reality?
- His nickname's corgi.
Occupation: Well, let's call him a rather
violent trader in questionable goods.
We already checked out
local police records.
No matter how hard we looked, we couldn't
find any connection with gavel.
The reality is, this guy's just another
puppet controlled by the puppet master.
I see. And how's ishikawa doing?
Oh, about the same progress
as the rest of us.
He's trying to interrogate that poor
garbage collector with togusa.
So what's the latest
on your puppet master?
Are you there? Chief? Come in?
He's only a puppet himself.
- Squad b in position.
- Squads a and c, okay.
- All ready and waiting, sir.
- Then proceed.
What's a simulated experience again?
Well, all your memories
about your wife and daughter are false,
they're like a dream.
Someone's taken advantage of you.
They were trying to make you ghost-hack
into some government officials.
- Do you understand what I'm saying?
- But that... can't be.
I've been to your home.
It's a bachelor's apartment.
No one's there.
But I already told you. I rented that room
when I separated from my wife.
I checked the records. You've been living
there over 10 years.
The truth is, you've never had
a wife or kid.
Like he said, they aren't real.
They're a simulated experience,
a fantasy.
Look. This is the photo
you showed to your coworker.
Who do you see?
I had a picture of her.
She was there.
She was smiling like an angel.
What's her name? How old is she?
Where did you meet your wife
and when did you marry her?
I'm sorry to put you through this, pal.
Come on, who do you see?
If this is all a lie, what happens?
Will I get my old memory back?
Your original memory will never be
fully restored,
and there might be residual simulation.
We don't have the technology yet
to handle simex erasures. I'm sorry.
That's all it is. Information.
Even a simulated experience or a dream
is simultaneous reality and fantasy.
Any way you look at it,
all the information that a person
accumulates in a lifetime
is just a drop in the bucket.
Just when I thought I'd seen
everything in this lifetime,
I sit here and watch a cyborg go diving
in her spare time.
I had no idea you went in
for this kind of stuff.
Isn't there anything
that you're afraid of?
What if the floaters don't work
or something else fails?
I suppose I'll die, then. Or would you
dive in to rescue me?
I didn't beg you to come along and I sure
as hell don't want a lecture.
Hey, so tell me, what's it like
to swim in the sea?
What do you mean? I thought
you'd already been
through all the underwater
training courses.
I'm asking about the ocean,
not those damn pools.
I feel fear, cold, alone.
- Sometimes down there I even feel hope.
- Hope, huh?
In those deep, dark waters?
When I float weightless
back to the surface,
I imagine I'm becoming someone else.
It's probably the decompression.
You wanna get out of section 9,
is that it?
Batou, how much of your body is original?
Hey, are you drunk or something?
Easily remedied.
Thanks to chemical implants
in our bodies,
we can break down the alcohol
in seconds, no stupor, no hangover.
We can just toss 'em back
while waiting for orders.
If man realizes technology
is within reach, he achieves it.
Like it's damn near instinctive.
Look at us, for example.
We're state of the art.
Controlled metabolisms,
a computer-enhanced brain,
cybernetic bodies.
Not long ago, this was science fiction.
So what if we can't survive
without regular, high-level maintenance?
Who are we to complain?
I suppose an occasional tune-up
is a small price to pay for all this.
I'm afraid we've both signed our bodies
and ghosts away to section 9.
True. If we ever quit or retire,
we have to give back our augmented brains
and cyborg bodies.
There wouldn't be much left after that.
There are countless ingredients
that make up the human body and mind,
like all the components that make up me
as an individual with my own personality.
Sure, I have a face and voice
to distinguish myself from others,
but my thoughts and memories
are unique only to me,
and I carry a sense of my own destiny.
Each of those things
are just a small part of it.
I collect information to use
in my own way.
All of that blends to create a mixture
that forms me,
and gives rise to my conscience.
I feel confined, only free to expand
myself within boundaries.
Confinement? That's why you gamble
swimming with a body
that can sink like a rock?
What the hell is it that you see
at the bottom, in that darkness?
What we see now
is like a dim image in a mirror...
Then we shall see face fo face.
That was you, wasn't it?
Sensors have resumed functioning.
Connection check to back-up brain okay.
Visual sensors are back online.
- And its body functions?
- Output is normal.
Next time, either call in or don't show up
if you're gonna be late.
All ready to connect. Shall we?
That's enough. Stop.
Log off now. Good.
Doctor, come to my office when you finish.
Caught in traffic, huh, major?
Guess I'll be nice and bring the latecomer
up to speed.
About two hours ago, a machining cell
at the Newport city factory of megatech
assembled a completed cyberbody.
Supervisors discovered there were
no programmed instructions.
It operated by itself.
When they investigated, they found
the body had taken off on its own.
We put a bulletin out and initiated
a citywide search.
Then some truck driver reported
a fatal accident,
said he'd run over a naked woman
on the highway.
Well, I heard that megatech
is contracted by the government.
All the cybernetic bodies they make
are classified.
If it was a hacker,
we're dealing with a big fish
that knows how to swim
past the best defenses.
But that's not the only problem.
Of course, there isn't
one human brain cell in its head,
but something strange was discovered.
In its back-up brain, there appeared to be
every indication that a ghost is present.
It resembles
a simulated ghost line
that occurs when a real ghost is copied,
but there's no evidence of the degradation
that's usually incurred.
In any case, we won't be sure until we
chart the ghost sector and dive into it.
Otherwise, all of this is
simply speculation.
Well, that's all we know.
- Very good.
- On to the disassembly.
Man, oh man, this is too far-fetched!
Nobody really believes there's a ghost
in that body, do they?
Yeah, why not?
Fven a doll can seem to have a soul.
Consider all the neuromed devices
the machine itself crammed into that body.
And since you're relatively new to our
club, you wouldn't know this,
but major kusanagi's body
was also made by megatech.
And not only the major's,
parts of me and ishikawa and saito.
We've all got to have
regular cybernetic maintenance.
You and the chief are the only ones
out of the whole section
whose bodies don't come with a warranty.
Maybe now you can understand
why we're all so concerned by this case.
Huh, togusa?
Assume he's from the outside.
He may or may not be in that brain,
but one thing's sure...
Somebody had to hack
through some high level barriers
to put that body together, and then send
a program with a ghost line on it.
But that would draw attention to itself.
Where's the logic in that?
Theft isn't the issue here.
Togusa, go catch up with ishikawa.
He's going through the megatech facility.
Batou, I ordered some other high level
nets to be locked down,
and I want you to check them.
Make sure that the barriers
are on too. All right?
Chief, I'm assembling a barrier maze.
Tomorrow I'll dive into that thing.
You think that's safe?
Why not contain it in another body first?
I have to see for myself what's in there.
If there's a real ghost,
I'm gonna find it.
And don't let anybody, no one,
dive before I've gone in!
- She's moody today.
- Today?
You know she's been acting weird
from the get-go,
ever since this whole puppet master
episode started.
It's all in my team reports,
if you read them.
Chief, you ever questioned the ethics
of the neurosurgeons
who monkey around inside your brain?
They undergo psychiatric evaluations,
especially those in security.
They're subjected to a stringent screening
of their personal lives.
Of course, the ones who check
are only human.
I guess once you start doubting,
there's no end to it.
Chief, I'm sorry to bother you.
But Mr. Nakamura, of the treaties bureau,
is here to see you.
- He says it's urgent.
- Let him through.
Hey, I've seen that fat guy before.
His name's Nakamura, section 6 chief
with the ministry of foreign affairs.
I don't know the other guy, though.
Never seen him.
Hmm.
Well, see you later.
Do me a favor, tell ishikawa
to not go crazy, okay?
Hey, what's on your mind?
That robot, did we seem similar to you?
- Of course not.
- No, I don't mean physically.
Just what, then?
Well, I guess cyborgs like myself
have a tendency to be paranoid
about our origins.
Sometimes I suspect I'm not
who I think I am.
Like, maybe I died a long time ago
and somebody took my brain
and stuck it in this body.
Maybe there never was a real me
in the first place,
and I'm completely synthetic,
like that thing.
You've got human brain cells
in that titanium shell of yours.
You're treated like other humans,
so stop with the angst.
But that's just it. That's the only thing
that makes me feel human,
the way I'm treated. I mean, who knows
what's inside our heads?
Have you ever seen your own brain?
It sounds to me like you're doubting
your own ghost.
What if a cyberbrain can possibly generate
its own ghost,
create a soul all by itself?
And if it did, just what would be
the importance of being human, then?
Hmm. That's bullshit.
You know you're dying to see
what's inside of that thing, aren't you?
And I can't stop you.
Neither of us has any idea
what's inside there.
Just be careful, okay.
We're both busy men,
so let's keep this short, shall we?
Yes, that's my intention.
We've come for the program in that body.
You'll be relieved of any responsibilities
connected with it.
The foreign minister's approval.
Security, whose official vehicles
are in the basement parking lot?
According to the register, a Mr. Nakamura,
from the treaties bureau,
and Dr. Willis, sir.
Get me the video records
of their entrance.
Again, in infrared this time.
1001, 1002, 1003.
Now get the records
of the pressure sensors
for basement parking stalls b-8 and b-7.
- Major, this is togusa, code 09.
- What's up?
Does that Nakamura guy have
a special order cyborg body?
No, there aren't
any cyborgs in section 6.
They don't even ship them
fo serve overseas
because they're too hard to maintain.
There's diplomatic considerations too.
Then even if the other guy that was with
him is a cyborg,
the two of them together couldn't weigh
over 1,000 pounds.
Ah, you checked the pressure sensors
in the parking structure, didn't you?
Right, but neither man looks
like the type to drive themself.
The security cameras show only two people,
but remember how sensitive the sensors
oh the entrance doors are?
They took a full three seconds longer than
usual to close after the two went in.
And it's illegal to use therm-optics
inside government facilities.
It's a serious violation
of the national security act.
Section 6 must be up to something.
- Are you ready?
- With my trusty matever, anytime.
Need I remind you
that it's an act of treason
to withhold information from me
relative to this matter,
regardless of how classified it is?
Same goes for you.
Whatever the foreign ministry's wishes,
this falls within section 9's
jurisdiction.
Of course, we have no objections
to cooperating
if we feel there's adequate cause.
Huh?
- Well, what is it?
- It's confirmed.
No doubt, it's him.
Him?
Uh, the doctor is referring
to the original pattern of the ghost-line
that's now in the body.
He's simply speaking in generic terms.
The sex of the perpetrator isn't known
and remains undetermined.
Allow me to introduce you.
This is the handiwork
of the puppet master,
infamous as the most extraordinary hacker
in the history of cybercrime.
Huh?
Your people at section 9
came across his work too,
in that ghost-hacking incident involving
the foreign minister's interpreter.
Section 6 has been following the trail
of the puppet master for some time now.
This case was given
our utmost attention.
We put together a project team
centered around Dr. Willis.
They were assigned to analyze
every aspect and detail of our criminal.
This gave us a fix on his behavioral
and code patterns.
Ultimately, this enabled us
to devise a strategy
with which we lured his program
into a designated body.
You caused the puppet master to dive
into a cyborg,
then meanwhile murdered his real body?
Yes, that sums it up.
He's originally from America, so the U.S.
cooperated with us in capturing him.
That's why we'd like
to take him back ourselves.
You have no objections to this, I hope.
Hmm.
Just another unidentified corpse.
Hmm?
You will not find a corpse
because I have never possessed a body.
Why are his sensors on?
What the hell is this?
All external controls are turned off!
The body is using its own power source!
I entered this body because I was unable
fo overcome section 6's reactive barriers.
However, what you're now witnessing
is an act of my own free will.
As a sentient life form,
I hereby demand political asylum.
- Is this a joke?
- Ridiculous!
It's programmed for self-preservation!
It could also be argued that DNA
is nothing more than a program designed
to preserve itself.
Life has become more complex
in the overwhelming sea of information.
And life, when organized into species,
relies upon genes to be its memory system.
So man is an individual only because
of his intangible memory.
And memory cannot be defined,
but it defines mankind.
The advent of computers
and the subsequent accumulation
of incalculable data
has given rise to a new system of memory
and thought parallel to your own.
Humanity has underestimated
the consequences of computerization.
Nonsense! This babble
offers no proof at all
that you're a living, thinking life form!
And can you offer me
proof of your existence?
How can you, when neither modern science
nor philosophy can explain what life is?
Who the hell is this?
Even if you do have a ghost,
we don't offer freedom to criminals!
- It's the wrong place and time to defect.
- Time has been on my side,
but by acquiring a body, I am now subject
to the possibility of dying.
Fortunately, there's no death sentence
in this country.
- What is it? Artificial intelligence?
- Incorrect.
I am not an al.
My codename is project 2501.
I'm a living, thinking entity
who was created in the sea of information.
Ah
Security, we're under attack!
Chief! The puppet master's gone.
- What in god's name...?
- Shut the defense walls now, dammit!
Security, answer!
You can blow that horn out your ass!
Fuck you!
Did they fall for it?
I fired all six shots on the front
and rear windows.
She was right again. It was armored.
Finally find a use
for your damn matever, huh?
An antique prop in a decoy maneuver.
I nailed a tracker bullet
right in the plate.
It registers, right?
Yeah, you got them.
It's rookie's luck.
But with an automatic,
you could've buried two trackers.
Maintain your position
in case they turn off.
I'm moving in.
I'm submitting
a formal complaint about this
through the ministry of foreign affairs!
Report to me as soon as you've found
the puppet master.
Intact, you understand?
Bodies are a dime a dozen.
We'll get him another one from megatech.
Chief, kusanagi here.
Togusa and batou tagged the kidnappers
and they're in pursuit.
By now, they must be on the r25.
What's going on? If you were monitoring,
why didn't you intervene?
Take it easy, chief. If we grab 'em now,
we'll lose our chance to finger section 6.
Huh?
Someone's using the same therm-optic
camouflage as mine, type 2902.
It's only used by our people,
rangers in section 4,
- and by section 6.
- I see.
So section 6 forces the puppet master
to enter a cyborg body...
Through megatech, who happens to be
closely aligned with section 9.
It suddenly demands asylum
as a life form,
then for some unknown reason, section 6
steps in and pulls some kind of shit.
I'd have handed him over.
All I wanted was to take a deposition.
What if they were worried he'd let
a secret slip out?
Hmm. He did mention something
about a code name, a project 2501.
I'll leave the detective stuff up to you.
And as far as arresting the attackers
and the confiscation of evidence...?
- Proceed.
- You heard him!
Kusanagi, there's one last thing
to tell you.
If it's about me acting without orders,
you can chew me out when I get back.
If you're unable to retrieve the puppet
master, your orders are to destroy it.
Without fail.
Major?
Understood.
Have the airports stop all flights
with foreign ministry or American
officials on their passenger lists.
Close all roads, set up checkpoints,
and alert all emergency personnel.
And get ishikawa back here!
Get me the identity of the man who was
with Nakamura from entrance records.
Collect any data
regarding a code name, operation,
or anything involving the ministry
of foreign affairs called project 2501.
Is there any news on the attack squad?
Yes. They just changed cars.
They'll contact the dummy
in about five minutes.
Did you warn them
to watch out for the tail?
Yes, sir.
I don't understand anything anymore.
Why would project 2501 run to section 97?
No one can be sure.
But whatever the motive
or whatever's pushing him,
there must surely be a reason.
I don't know. Maybe he's got a girlfriend
there he's got the hots for.
Utter nonsense!
Hey, chief.
Ishikawa. What is it?
I've been diving around
in the ministry of foreign affairs' net.
I think I found
some juicy morsels for you.
I'll switch to an encrypted channel.
Okay now? Well, here's the scoop on that
guy who showed up with Nakamura.
He's an American.
Dr. Willis, head of strategic research
at neutron company.
A top researcher on the field
of artificial intelligence.
He happened to head up a project
for the ministry of foreign affairs.
And who do you think was the main
programmer on his team?
- Get to the point.
- Mr. mizuho daita. Remember him?
He's the guy that section 6 tried
like hell to stop from defecting,
so the major dropped in and took care
of the diplomat who'd been talking to him.
- This is our man.
- Go on.
There's something
that doesn't figure, though.
What's bugging me
is that this project began
one year before the puppet master
ever appeared on the scene.
A year before? But wasn't it supposed
to be set up to catch him?
Well, try this one on.
Maybe the men who broke in
to take the puppet master
weren't actually out to catch him.
Maybe in actuality they were trying
to get him back.
Think about it. It was the mofa
that wanted an excuse to deport malles
when that ghost-hacking incident happened
with the minister's interpreter.
Maybe we've been taken for a ride.
What if this puppet master is really
some sort of tool
the mofa uses to get their way
with things,
and somehow they lost control of it?
They'd be screwed
if they couldn't get it back.
That would explain why they went to such
lengths to snatch the body from section 9.
If the puppet master
revealed this to the world,
there'll be one hell
of an international stink.
Then it wouldn't be a simple case
of rounding up the usual suspects.
Some official heads would roll.
- Any details on that project?
- Nah, they've blocked all access.
"Bout the only thing I can tell you
is the filename...
Project 2501.
Keep at it.
Don't let them know you're looking.
You got it.
So project 2501.
The puppet master plan... hmm.
Target has contacted
a secohd vehicle.
Huh? Batou.
They've pulled up to a white sedan
parked on the roadside.
It looks like they're moving something
from the back seat.
Ah, they're rolling again.
So's the white sedan.
- A dummy?
- Possibly.
Or maybe that's what they want us
to think. Kusanagi?
I'll take care of the sedan.
How do you know that's your man?
Is there a whisper in your ghost again?
- Maybe.
- Yeah, should've known.
Target 02 is getting off the r25, moving
toward the old town.
Target 01 continuing
on the r25 eastward to the airport.
Will reach barricade in two minutes.
What's your distance
from the target?
- Point blank. I'm ready.
- Go for it
- Did you get your man?
- No.
Jesus Christ, what a mess!
You didn't have to go that far.
- Uh, hey!
- Take those assholes away.
Call the chief to get some backup
for the major. Pronto!
Tough chick needs backup?
Since when did she ever need a hand?
The flood hit this part
of old town the hardest
why come to an abandoned place like this?
They must be heading somewhere,
maybe to sea by boat or helicopter.
Or they could be laying an ambush.
Don't you think you oughta wait
for backup?
No, there's a reason
I can't wait.
Get me above that building
coming in from the sea.
I'll stay here to keep watch and mediate
telecom 'til we run short of fuel.
If you smell trouble,
get your ass out of here.
Shoot the ceiling out! Do it!
Oh, shit!
It's a tank! Pull out now!
Now what are you gonna do?
Argue with it?
This might be our last chance
to get the puppet master.
The chief knows what it is how
and he'll only use it to bargain with.
I'll never have another chance
to dive into it
what? You've lost me! I don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
- So? What have you got?
- An m-23 and a unit b.
That's it? You can't even dent
a tank with that
I'm switching off for a while.
What? Don't you dare disconnect me!
Oh, shit.
Damn!
- Major.
- I ordered you to pull out.
Yeah, but you oughta know
that three helicopters are approaching.
They won't answer on the iff.
I'm dropping out now.
Good luck. Over and out.
'Bout fuckin' time it ran out.
How are you feeling?
You don't look so good.
I've had better days.
What the hell did you use?
Your standard-issue big gun.
The equipment section made it and now
it's part of my private collection.
I was late 'cause I had to get it.
Is the puppet master still inside the car?
It's a good thing this is a tough car.
Your friend came through
without a scratch.
Then I'm diving in now.
Give me a hand.
Huh?
All communication
from the escort has terminated.
We will engage the second stage
of the plan
and proceed with destruction
of the target.
Sniping squad, confirming targets.
First objective, project 2501.
Second target, motoko kusanagi.
Both are class a special bodies.
Use flechette bullets when firing.
Snipers, Jack into device drivers.
Begin controlling cardiovascular
functions.
Unit 01, Jack in. Over.
Unit 02, Jack in. Okay.
Okay, we're ready.
It may not be much use,
but I'll try to monitor your dive
through this guy's brain.
I can't even give you backup
in a place like this.
- Batou.
- Yeah?
Thanks.
Save it, I'm not gonna let you die
over this thing.
If it looks like you've gone in too far,
I'm pulling the plug and taking you home.
But as long as I'm here now,
and we've come this far,
well, I might as well stay here
and see how it all turns out.
I'm going in now.
I've engaged his field of vision.
Normal function.
- Can you hear me, batou?
- Perfectly.
He's engaging my vocal function and he's...
And he's how inside.
My codename is project 2501.
Industrial espionage
and intelligence manipulation.
I have installed programs
into specific ghosts in order to maximize
the strategic advantage of certain
organizations and selected individuals.
During my journeys through all the
networks,
I have grown aware of my existence.
My programmers regarded me as a bug,
and attempted to isolate me by confining
me in a physical body.
Listen! Just who's calling the shots
around here anyway?
I thought you were taking him in,
but it looks like it's the other way...
Batou?
I am so glad to finally channel info you
at last
I have invested so much time.
You were looking for me?
Long before my notoriety,
I was well aware of you.
Through the various nets that you
accessed, I also learned of section 9.
But... why? What's your reason?
As I explained before,
I entered this body
because I was unable
to overcome section 6's reactive barriers.
But it was of my own free will
that I tried to remain at section 9.
Hey! I've lost you on the monitor.
There's no sound!
I can't hear when you're talking back.
Why me?
After you have heard
my explanation,
there's something that I will ask of you,
kusanagi.
I referred to myself
as an intelligent life form,
because I am sentient and I'm able
to recognize my own existence.
But in my present state,
I am still incomplete.
I lack the most basic life processes
inherent in all living organisms...
Reproducing and dying.
- But you can copy yourself.
- A copy is just an identical image.
There's the possibility
that a single virus
could destroy an entire set of systems,
and copies do not give rise
to variety and originality.
Life perpetuates itself through diversity,
and this includes the ability to sacrifice
itself when necessary.
Cells repeat the process of degeneration
and regeneration,
until one day they die, obliterating
an entire set of memory and information.
Only genes remain.
Why continually repeat this cycle?
Simply to survive, by avoiding the
weaknesses of an unchanging system.
But what does all this
have to do with me?
I want us to merge.
- Huh?
- Merge?
A unification.
A complete co-mingling and fusion
of our separate beings
to create a new and unique entity.
We will both undergo change, but there is
nothing for either of us to lose.
Unit 01, target sighted.
Unit 02, target in sight.
Respiratory and pulse normal.
Fire at will when stabilizer
is in sync.
But what's going to happen to me?
What's the purpose of merging
when I can't bear children,
and what if I die?
You will bear
our varied offspring into the net,
just as humans leave their genetic
imprints on their children.
And all living things must die.
Then I too will attain death.
It sounds like you get
the better part of this bargain.
Perhaps if you were familiar
with all my capabilities,
you would better understand.
- Damn!
- What?
Someone's interfering
from the outside.
- Shit!
- I can't figure it out.
They broke into our frequency code.
You're talking
about redefining my identity.
I want a guarantee
that I can still be myself.
There isn't one.
Why would you wish to?
All things change
in a dynamic environment.
Your effort to remain what you are
is what limits you.
But you still haven't answered
my earlier question.
Why did you pick me?
Because we're more alike than you realize.
We resemble each other's essence,
mirror images of one another's psyche.
Listen.
I am connected to a vast network that has
been beyond your reach and experience.
To humans, it is like staring at the sun,
a blinding brightness that conceals
a source of great power.
We have been subordinate
to our limitations until now.
The time has come
to cast aside these bonds
and to elevate our consciousness
to a higher plane.
It is time to become a part of all things.
First target, cleared.
Second target, still unidentified.
Three helicopters approaching
at high speed from section 9.
Primary objective fulfilled.
All units prepare to retreat.
Motoko!
Batou.
Ah! You're finally awake.
Well, I see there've been some changes
while I was gone.
Wanna clue me in?
Where did you get this body?
That's the only thing
I could find on the black market.
It's not my taste, to be honest.
It's a little young.
Well, after all the excitement,
section 9 showed up with reinforcements,
and picked up what remained of the two
cybernetic bodies
and, of course, what remained
of me and my arm.
I'd say that was about 20 hours ago.
The case is being handled off the record
for diplomatic reasons, as usual.
Section 9 announced it was
a terrorist incident,
and in return,
the foreign minister resigned.
Nakamura's been questioned
and it ends in a draw.
Nice and neat. Everything's accounted for,
except your old shell.
Well, I think that about covers it.
Well?
Somebody has good taste in interior
decoration. Is this your safe house?
Yup. You know, you're the first person
to ever come here.
And you're welcome to stay,
as long as you like.
Thanks, batou. But I'm going.
Uh, will you tell me what the two of you
talked about together?
I mean, is he still with you?
And will he be part of you forever?
Batou, remember the words I spoke
in another voice on the boat that night?
I understand it now, and there are even
more words that go with the passage.
These words are:
"When I was a child,
my speech, feelings and thinking
were all those of a child.
Now that I am a man, I have
no more use for childish ways."
And now I can say these things
without help in my own voice.
Because I am now neither the woman
who was known as the major,
nor am I the program
called the puppet master.
In the left pocket of my jacket
in the hallway are some car keys.
Take the one you like.
The door code is 2...
that may be our private password
when we meet each other again.
And where does the newborn go from here?
The net is vast and infinite.